俺たちは変わる  勝って　それを証明してやる！
We'll change.
We'll win and prove it to them!
That's right, we can do it!
やれる　やれるぞ！
The game is slowly turning in our favor!
完全にウチらのペース！
United we stand, Fly a flag!
「Ｕｎｉｔｅｄ　ｗｅ　ｓｔａｎｄ，　Ｆｌｙ　ａ　ｆｌａｇ 風を受け止めて」
kaze o uketomete
風を受け止めて
Let the wind blow through you
United we stand, Fly a flag!
「Ｕｎｉｔｅｄ　ｗｅ　ｓｔａｎｄ，　Ｆｌｙ　ａ　ｆｌａｇ たなびけ勝利のｆｌａｇ」
tanabike shouri no flag
たなびけ勝利の flag
Let the victory flag trail in the wind
「遥かなゴールを信じて 走り続けて」
haruka na gooru o shinjite
遥かなゴールを信じて
Believe in the goal that lies in wait and keep running
hashiri tsuzuketeke
走り続けてけ
「日々夢紡ぐ者達へ 降り注げ光よ」
hibi yume tsumugu monotachi e furisosoge hikari yo
日々夢紡ぐ者達へ降り注げ光よ
Let light pour down upon the weaver of dreams
「汗は裏切らないって 唇噛み締め」
ase wa uragiranaitte kuchibiru kamishime
汗は裏切らないって唇噛み締め
Your sweat won't betray you, so bite down on your lips
「何度も立ち上がり 大地を駆け抜ける」
nandomo tachiagari daichi o kakenukeru
何度も立ち上がり大地を駆け抜ける
And stand back up again and again as you dash across the earth
「夢に終わりはないって 目を輝かせ」
yume ni owari wa naitte me o kagayakase
夢に終わりはないって 目を輝かせ
Our dreams never end, so keep on shining
「Ｌｅｔ’ｓ　ｓｔａｒｔ　ｎｏｗ ＧＩＡＮＴ　ＫＩＬＬＩＮＧ」
Let's start now GIANT KILLING!
「ｆｏｒ　ｔｈｅ　ｒｉｇｈｔ ｈｏｌｄ　ｏｎ　ｔｉｇｈｔ」
For the right! Hold on tight!
「ｍｙ　ｓｔｏｒｙ…」
My story...
Forever...
「ｆｏｒｅｖｅｒ」
Like I said, I'm just going out for a while!
だから　ちょっとだけって 言ってんだろ！
そう言って　あんた　いつも 試合後　シゲちゃんたちと
Even so, you'll always end up drinking with Shige after the match!
飲みに行くんでしょうが！ ち　違えよ　俺は…
Y-You're wrong! I'm just...
What's with that outfit, then?
じゃ　何だい？　その格好は  う…
わ～！　もう後半 始まってんじゃねえか！
It's already the second half!
I'm going out for a bit!
ちょっくら行ってくらあ！ ちょ　ちょっと待ちな　あんた！
H-Hold on! Stop right there, you stupid husband!
このバカ亭主～！
There's no way I'm missing this!
見逃せるかいってんだよ  達海のリーグ開幕戦だぞ
It's Tatsumi's opening match today!
During the match against Tokyo Victory, Tatsumi was only giving instructions in the technical area.
東京ヴィクトリー戦  達海はベンチから
指示を出していただけだったのに まるで　１０年前みたいに
It's just like ten years ago!
ワクワクする試合を見せてくれた  やっぱり達海はスゲエ！
I'm so excited!
Tatsumi's amazing! He's still able to show us such exciting stuff as a manager!
監督になっても 面白い事してくれる
With him at the helm,
あいつなら　本当に　ＥＴＵを 優勝させちまうかもしれねえ！
ETU may just be able to win the league!
ゴール！　４点目！
Goal! It's the fourth one!
What's this? They're being ripped apart.
何よ　これ  ボロボロじゃない
They started off well, but crumbled and faded away as the game wore on.
序盤のいい形が 跡形も無く崩れ去ったわね
The first goal.
１点目のゴール
あの直後から　ＥＴＵは　たがが 外れたように無茶苦茶になった
Right after the first goal, ETU's formation went into a mess, just like a broken chain.
Get to the goal now! Hurry!
ボール！　早く！
Stop your aimless running, Tsubaki! Calm down!
闇雲に走るな　椿！ 落ち着け！
Hurry up and get back into position! Do you even intend to defend at all?
戻り遅えんだよ！ 守る気あんのかよ　おい！
Why? That initial goal was just a complete fluke. It shouldn't have affected them much, right?
何で？　１点目は ただのラッキーゴールじゃない
引きずるもんじゃ ないでしょ
Is it really alright for me to follow up on such a team?
私は本当に　こんなチームを 追っかけてて　いいわけ？
よっと
へへへへ　手応えがあったとはお世辞にもいえんな
They look so down that I don't even know how to comfort them.
新チームの脆さが出たか　達海よ
The cracks are showing up on your new team, Tatsumi...
負けました
We've lost.
非常に残念
It was a pity.
悔しい
I'm gutted.
終わり
That is all.
やっぱり　まともなこと言わねーな
As I expected, he's not worth listening to at all.
それでは　質問のある方
You can now start asking questions.
The female reporter over there.
じゃあ　そちらの女性の方
はい　フリーの藤澤です
Thanks.
I'm Fujisawa, a freelance writer.
監督はプレスカンファレンスで
During the conference, you mentioned about transforming the Japanese league into an exciting one.
日本のサッカー界を面白くするとおっしゃいました
あの宣言に心を躍らせた人は
I believe that a lot of people were encouraged by your words.
きっと少なくないと思います
ですが　今日の試合は
However,
The performance today betrayed those who believe in what you said.
そうした人たちの思いを　裏切った形になりましたよね
藤澤さん　いうね
Miss Fujisawa sure isn't mincing her words.
Are you still expecting these people to harbor that hope?
それでも　まだ期待しろと言い切れますか
Well, what?
はい？
怒ってんの？
Are you angry?
怒ってません　質問に答えてください
I'm not, please answer my question!
うんん　怒ってんじゃん
So you are angry.
怒ってませんてば
I said I'm not!
だって顔怖いもん
But your expression doesn't indicate so!
What are you talking about?
何を失礼な！
You're rude!
こういう顔なんです
Am I?
What should I do?
どうしよう
なんなのコイツ！
What's with this guy? I've had enough! I'm not gonna bet my whole year on him!
もう嫌だ
私の一年間は賭けられない！
今からでも私はほかのクラブを……
There's still time. I can still request for a change of clubs!
You can.
いいよ
期待してくれて　大いに結構！
You guys can continue to believe in me.
2nd half of league game
Sun Arrow Hiroshima vs ETU
椿　もっと上がれよ
Tsubaki, hurry up and catch up!
We won't win if we can't score!
点取んなきゃ勝てねえんだぞ
You're running way ahead, Tsubaki!
出すぎだ椿！バカ野郎
You turd!
次取られたら終わるぞ！
We're finished if we concede another!
椿　上がれよ
Catch up, Tsubaki!
戻れってんだよ　椿！
I told you to come back, Tsubaki!
何度言ったら分かるんだ！
How many times do I need to tell you guys?! The space!
スペース！！
中央のスペースが空きすぎてるんだ！
There's way too much space in midfield!
修正する気あるのか！！
Are you all really putting in effort?!
聞けよ　お前たち
We'll lose if we carry on like this, you hear me?!
このままじゃ今日も負けるぞ！！
期待しろなんて言っておきながら
He was still confidently telling me to believe in him... What the hell are they doing?
何よ　このざま
広島まで来てやったってのに
And I took such a long trip to Hiroshima.
We lost again.
また負けた　リーグ戦二連敗
Two consecutive league losses...
何でですかね——
What in the world happened?
あれほど緒戦の失敗を反省して臨んだのに
We did learn from our mistakes from the opening loss and improve...
連敗もですが
That's two straight losses, and we haven't even scored a single goal. It's a real headache.
2試合　無得点というのが　また
胃をキリキリとさせるというか……
Who's that laughing just now?!
今　笑ったの誰だ　コラア！！
聞こえだぞ！！
I heard that!
連敗だってのにヘラヘラしやがって！！
We've already lost twice in a row, and yet you're still laughing.
こういう時こそなぁ！
We need to come together to raise morale in this kind of situation!
チームの意識がひとつになんなきゃいけねえんだよ！
またか
Here...
...we go again.
始まったよ
笑ってたの　多分　王子だ
The one laughing just now must be Gino.
もういいじゃないスか
Forget it.
みんな疲れてんスよ
Everyone's tired.
なんだ　赤崎
What's that, Akasaki?
守備しねーやつが疲れたとかぬかすのかよ
The one not defending during the match dares to say that he's tired.
Thanks to you guys storming forward, the opponent made use of the space in midfield.
オメーらが上がりすぎてっから
中盤で好きにやられてんじゃねーか！
いい加減考えて動けよ　ボケ！
You guys have to use your brains before you act, dumbass!
何言ってんスか　自分らがビビって
What are you saying?
It's because you're too afraid of your opponents that you sit way too deep!
ディフェンスライン　下げてんじゃないスか
ああ？ 俺はちゃんとやってますよ
I am definitely giving my all.
You should reflect on your own performance before criticizing others!
他人に　どうこう言う前に 自分の反省したらどうスか？
In truth, we've conceded way too many.
実際　失点多いんだし
Don't screw with me, you bastard!
この～！　ふざけんじゃねえぞ テメエ　コラ！ イテ！
Ouch!
うわあ　やっぱり始まった！
Crap, it started!
Stop it, Kuro!
やめろ　クロ  俺らはバランス考えてやってんだ
We only did that to maintain the balance of the team!
What?
Don't give me that know-it-all face!
知った口 きいてんじゃねえよ！
Murakoshi, is this alright?
コシさん　いいんスか？
Leave them be...
ほっとけよ  え？
試合後に 騒ぐ元気がある時点で
If they can still quarrel after a match, it means we've lost a game that we were destined to lose.
今日は負けるべくして負けたって ことだろ
離せよ　スギ  あ！
Let me go, Sugi!
He's also looking down on you! Do you intend to let him continue his wayward thinking?
こいつは　お前のことも バカにしてんだぞ
なめられっぱなしで いいのかい！
This is not the place to fight, Kuro.
場所を考えろ　クロ  そういう思いは
It'll be a mess if we let this happen again during tomorrow's training.
明日の練習に ぶつけりゃいいだろ
何だよ椿　コラ  テメエもいいかげんにしとけよ
What happened, Tsubaki?
You better get your act up. You're useless in both attack and defense.
攻撃も守備も　どっちつかずでよ  使えねえんだよ　オメエはよ！
You're really trash!
まずいですよ　監督  これで雰囲気まで悪くなっては…
This doesn't look good, manager!
If the team morale were to get any worse...
Macchan...
松ちゃん  はい！
Yes?
What kind of games do you like?
ゲーム　何が好き？
W-What are you talking about?
あ…　あのう 一体何の話？
This is an important question.
大事な質問だよ
そうですねぇ… 強いて言えば
Let's see...
If I have to pick one, I would say it's Shogi.
私　こう見えて将棋が…  やっぱ　あれだな
Just as I expected, it's that!
はあ？ あれにしよ 　うん
Let's play that then.
監督　大丈夫なのか？ チームが　こんな状態なのに
Manager, are you okay?
The squad is already a mess, but...
不安だ…　不安だ
I'm so worried. Very worried.
おう　後藤
Gotou...
Tatsumi.
達海　俺は お前を信頼してるから
I have lots of faith in you.
Hey, I have a question for you.
あのさあ 聞きたい事があったんだ
How many more games can I lose before I get the sack?
俺　解任まで あと何連敗できる？
Stop screwing around with me.
ふざけんじゃねえぞ  あの野郎
That asshole!
何で俺らが　スタメン外されなきゃ なんねえんだよ
Why did we have to be dropped to the bench?
あんなガキがやるような 遊びの結果でよ！
All because of the outcome of some kids game!
What? A game competition?
はあ？　ゲーム大会？
Right.
うん 　では　アシスタントの松ちゃん 説明を
And so, let's have my assistant, Macchan, to explain the details.
Y-Yes.
は　はい 　「種目はサッカーテニス  ペアを組んで行います
The game will be 'Soccer-Tennis'. You'll pair up in twos to play.
The pair with the highest score will be awarded with a fabulous prize.
成績上位ペアには なんと豪華商品も」
Put some enthusiasm in your instructions!
あ～　もっと元気よく読んでよ  ああ　はい
Yes.
For your partner, you are to pair up with a player of the same position.
「それと　ペアは　なるべく同じ ポジションの人と組んでください」
「それでは皆さん 優勝を目指して　エイ　エイ　オ～」
Therefore, everyone...
Aim for first place!
Aye, aye, ooo...
あ～あ　もう！ 松ちゃんのせいで台なしだよ
Man, you wasted such a cool line!
I put in so much effort to write this.
頑張って書いたのに  はあ…
Let's start then!
じゃあ　やるよ～  ペア組んで
Form your teams now!
Oi, Manager!
おいおい　おいおい 監督さんよ～！
はぁ～　俺ら　なにも 休みが欲しいわけじゃねえんだよ
We don't need time for a rest to play a few games...
むしろ　ガチガチに練習してえの  あんたも昔
We have to concentrate on working hard in training!
You were once a player yourself,
選手だったんなら　わかんだろ  連敗してる時の気持ちはよぉ
You should know what it feels like to lose two consecutive matches!
ホラ　練習しましょうや 練習
Alright, let's practice!
俺　そういう時も よくやったけどな　この遊び
But I did play that kind of games too during my player days...
あ…　遊びぃ？ 何はっきり言ってんだよ！
G-Game?
How can you still say that with a straight face? So it's still a game!
やっぱり 遊びなんじゃねえか！
Didn't I just say it's a game competition?
だから　ゲーム大会だって 言ってんじゃんよ
ふ　ふざけんな！ すぐ次の試合があんだよ
Quit joking around! The third match's coming soon and there is no time for games!
遊んでる暇なんて ねえんだよ！
We're different from the lame team you managed back in England!
俺らはな　あんたが率いていた イングランドのアマチュアとは　違えんだよ
Are we playing this in order to win?
勝つためにやるのか？ うん？
Of course.
当然
椿  は…　はい
Tsubaki.
Y-Yes?
Team up with me.
組むぞ  えっ
Don't we need to pair up with a player of the same position?
同じポジションのヤツが 組むんだろ？
コシさんがやるんなら  ああ
Since Murakoshi wants to play, why don't we...
Yeah.
サイドバック同士だし  おう
Then we side-backs should team up.
おりゃっ！
おっしゃ～　同点！ やった！
Alright! We've leveled!
Amazing! Keep it up!
うめえ！ いや～　ラリー続くねえ！
ドリさん　すっげえヘッド！ フォワードもいけますよ　ドリさん
Dori, that's a great move!
It's as if you can play as a striker too, Dori!
Alright, 20-0. We've lost.
はい　２０対０ うちらの負け
終わりだ　終わり 　こんな くだらねえ事　やってられっか
It's over! Who would play this kind of boring game?
You shouldn't be doing this, Kuro.
ヤバくないスか？　クロさん  一応　監督の考えた事なんだし
After all, it's still something devised by the manager.
言う事　聞いといたほうが…
It's better to heed his advice.
本人が遊びだって言ってんだ  関係ねえよ
He said it's just a game himself!
That's not the point.
それより俺は 勝つために努力したいね
I will only make the effort if it concerns winning a game.
Hey Tatsumi, do you have any collection of your interest?
ねえねえ　タッツミーは何か 集めてる物ある？　僕　最近
I have a bit of an interest in chairs lately.
イスに凝っててさ　だから 僕が勝ったら豪華商品をイスに…
Therefore if I win, please give me a comfy chair as a prize.
Not possible.
なりません  そっか
Is that so? Well, the chair that I fancy does cost two million yen.
ま　僕が欲しいのは ２００万するしね
豪華商品は…  うん？
The fabulous prize is...
次のゲームの出場権です
A starting place for the next game!
えっ？ …え～っ
えいっ！
今シーズン初得点だ～！
The first goal of the season!
よっしゃ～！
Yes!
Great! Nice goal, Sera!
よ～し！　ナイスゴール世良！ 赤崎も　ナイスアシスト！
Akasaki's assist is nice too!
No matter how much more we throw at them, it's still not enough!
騒いだところで 後の祭りじゃねえかよ
小林も亀井も 悪い選手じゃねえけどよ
Kobayashi and Kame ain't that bad of a player too.
I have to look over my shoulders now...
後ろ 抜かれまくりなんだよ
That bastard.
あの　クソ野郎 　うちらを 後半から出すんだったら
If he had put us on for the second half, we might have been able to get a narrow win.
許す余地もあったけどよ
What's the matter, Sugi?
あ？　どうしたよ　スギ？
Oh, nothing.
ああ…　いや
Look. It's gonna end. Serves him right.
ほら見ろ　終わるぜ  ザマぁねえや
はあ～　また負けたぁ
We lost again.
We've lost three in a row!
開幕３連敗かよ！
This is really...
こいつは　さすがに… 辛抱ならねえな
...pushing our patience to the limit.
俺　決めたぜ　スギ
I've decided, Sugi.
I need to transfer clubs! I'm not playing under him anymore!
移籍だ　移籍！　俺　もう あいつの下じゃ　やれねえ！
A transfer? Kuroda?
移籍？　黒田が？
まあ　感情が高ぶって ほえてるだけだと思うんですけど
Though I think he's just saying it in the heat of the moment.
But I would want to hear your opinion, Dori.
一応　ドリさんの意見も 聞いておこうかと思って
ほう　珍しいな　杉江  そういう話は
That's a rare occurrence, Sugi.
Isn't this a matter you would normally ask Murakoshi?
いつも村越に してるんじゃないのか？
Yeah, but...
そうなんですけど コシさん最近
Recently, Murakoshi has...
...been giving off a sense of unapproachability.
何か他人を寄せつけない 感じなんスよ
It's like he has become a lone wolf.
一匹狼みたいっていうか
That's true.
確かにな 　ま 責任感でできてるような男だ
However, he is a man with a strong sense of responsibility.
ヤツなりの考えが あってのことだろう
He has his own set of opinions too.
I feel the same for Tatsumi too.
達海さんも同じだと思うぜ  え？
あの人なりの 考えがあるんだろうよ
He also has his way of thinking.
Using that kind of game to determine the starting line-up.
あんなゲームで試合に出る選手決めて 反発したくなるのは
It's not only Kuroda that's feeling a sense of exhalation.
何も黒田だけじゃないだろう  あれが遊びだってんなら
If that's a game, then he has his own reasons for using it to plot his course of action.
きっと遊びでなきゃいけない 理由があるはずなんだ
俺は　達海さんはそういう人だと 思うぜ 　根拠はないけどな
I feel that Tatsumi is that kind of a person.
Though it's only my feelings.
Before letting Kuroda decide on whether to change clubs, make sure that he's putting himself in other people's shoes.
黒田も移籍しちまう前に　１回 そこまで考えてみたらどうだ
Dori...
ドリさん
I still have something to ask you.
ドリさんに　もう一つ 聞きたいことがあるんスけど
どうしよう… 監督に言うべきか？
What should I do?
Should I tell the manager?
But Kuroda handed in a transfer request,
でも　黒田が移籍をほのめかしてる なんて　立派な監督批判だし…
That's obviously showing a sign of dissatisfaction towards the manager.
ここは私が穏便に…
I'll just try to mediate here...
Well,
え～　今回も スタメン争奪ゲーム大会を行いま～す
We will now also conduct a competition to determine the starting line-up.
ええっ また
Again?
It's not gonna work, manager! That was the reason why we lost the previous game!
監督　きついっスよ  前回　それで負けてるんスよ
コシさんなんて 椿が足引っ張ったせいで
It was because of Tsubaki's failings that Murakoshi had to be subbed off so early in the match!
あやうく 脱落しかけたんスよ
That was only a reference.
あくまで参考だよ　参考  それがすべてじゃないよ
The end product is not everything.
でも　実際 クロとスギが…
But in truth, Kuroda and Sugi have...
やってられっか
That's about all I can take...
あ　クロ  …おい　クロ！
Kuro!
Hey, Kuro!
This is bad.
最悪だ…　冗談じゃなく 最悪の展開になっちまった
It's no joke. Things really are turning for the worse.
試合に出たくないヤツは やんなくていいよ
Those who don't feel like playing the next match are allowed to not participate.
However, those who want to win the next game...
ただ　試合に出て勝ちたいヤツは ガキみたいに一生懸命遊ぶこと！
Go ahead and enjoy the competition!
「Ｙｏｕ’ｖｅ　ｇｏｔ　ｆｉｎｄ　ｔｈｅ　ｗａｙ　ｔｏ ｂｅｌｉｅｖｅ，　ｃａｒｒｙ　ｏｎ　ａｎｄ　ｃａｒｒｙ　ｏｎ」
You've got find the way to believe
Carry on and carry on
Till you can see tomorrow
「Ｔｉｌｌ　ｙｏｕ　ｃａｎ　ｓｅｅ ｔｏｍｏｒｒｏｗ， Ｉ’ｌｌ　ｓａｙ　“ｎｅｖｅｒ　ｌｏｏｋ　ｂａｃｋ”」
I'll say “never look back”
「追い風を待って そうｃｈａｎｃｅを のがすなら」
oikaze o matte
追い風を待って
Wait for the tailwind
sou chance o nogasunara
そう chance を逃すなら
And if you missed the chance
「自分が風になれ　ｎｏ　ｆｅａｒｓ， ｎｏ　ｔｅａｒｓ，　ｙｅｓ　Ｌｅｔ　ｉｔ　ｇｏ！」
jibun ga kaze ni nare
自分が風になれ
Become the wind yourself
No fears! No tears! Yes! Let it go!
「Ｇｅｔ　ｔｏｕｇｈ！（Ｓｔａｙ　ｇｏｌｄ！） Ｇｅｔ　ｔｏｕｇｈ！（Ｗｅ’ｌｌ　ｇｏ！）」
Get tough! Get tough!
Stay gold!
We'll go!
genkai oikose yuke
限界追い越せ行け
Surpass your limits and go!
「限界追い越せ 行け　キツイほど ｈｅａｒｔ　ｉｎ　ｒｅｄ」
kitsui hodo heart in red
キツイほど　heart in red
The harder it is the redder your heart will be!
「Ｇｏ　ｏｎ！ （Ｓｔａｙ　ｃｏｏｌ！） Ｇｏ　ｏｎ！（Ｗｅ’ｌｌ　ｇｏ！）」
Go on! Go on!
Stay cool!
We'll go!
「あすは見えない　だから」
asu wa mienai dakara
あすは見えないだから
Because we can't see into the future
「Ｉｔ’ｓ　ｔｉｍｅ　ｔｏ　ｇｏ やめられない」
It's time to go yamerarenai
It's time to go やめられない
So it's time to go. We can't quit!
「Ｇｅｔ　ｔｏｕｇｈ！ Ｇｅｔ　ｔｏｕｇｈ！　Ｇｅｔ　ｔｏｕｇｈ！」
Get tough!
「Ｇｅｔ　ｔｏｕｇｈ！（Ｓｔａｙ　ｇｏｌｄ！） Ｇｅｔ　ｔｏｕｇｈ！（Ｗｅ’ｌｌ　ｇｏ！）」
Get tough! Get tough!
Stay gold!
We'll go!
「共に乗り越えて　行け 見えるか　Ｉｔ’ｓ　ｄａｙｂｒｅａｋ　ｔｈｅｒｅ」
tomo ni norikoete yuke
共に乗り越えて行け
Let's get through it together
mieruka It's daybreak there
見えるか It's daybreak there
Can you see that it's daybreak there?
「Ｇｏ　ｏｎ！（Ｓｔａｙ　ｃｏｏｌ！）　Ｇｏ　ｏｎ！ （Ｗｅ’ｌｌ　ｇｏ！）　予測できない」
Go on! Go on!
Stay cool!
We'll go!
yosoku dekinai dakara
予測できないだから
The future is unpredictable
「だから　Ｉｔ’ｓ　ｔｉｍｅ　ｔｏ　ｇｏ 止められない」
It's time to go tomerarenai
It's time to go 止められない
So it's time to go. We can't stop!
The person that we have to defeat...
...is ourselves.
We didn't change.
We've only thought that we changed.
Damn it!
To have their places taken away by the youngsters...
It should be about time...